check okay I think kokanee is actually
like a Canadian beer coke music Amy I
think so like I remember something my
cousin was talking about where he
thought you have to find Sasquatch on
the container like on the book on the
bottles yeah like you search for it that
is the coolest business model to have we
just thank you got a secret Yeti just
hiding out and your do you believe in
Sasquatch I believe there could be
something out there but it's also I
don't really swim it's a slim chance
it's a slim chance what what is the
story of Sasquatch even is it like is it
just there's some some evolutionary it's
not an ape it's not a human but it's a
thing and he has survived but he's just
elusive I feel like someone got really
bored in high school and they just
dressed up and some fur cost you maybe
he'll read video and someone saw
everyone's gonna believe it I mean we
kind of see it a lot so the the weed
store here for example right next door
is the weed story Council Ron no there
is yeah marijuana store yeah you can buy
marijuana in Castle Rock Washington yeah
it's next to make the mountain
yeah the mountains gifts I think it's
okay yeah oh I know the one I used to go
there all the time as a young woman you
used to every Sunday mom took me to the
Mount st. Helens gift see what they got
in all right well we are in my friend
Nona
Wynonna Southard what do you typically
like to go go by now that you're older I
just go by Nona oh is it just me that
just puts Wynonna in front of it just I
think everybody just assumes that it's
Wynonna because that's my technical name
a technical name did you have anything
against it when you were younger like do
not come today do you don't put that Y
in there I hated it because everyone
would just automatically assume that I
was Wynonna Judd or
a writer that's not what I'm named after
this is like a super intelligent
unintelligent way to take any
conversation like your name is like this
name okay what do you want to say about
that
well I'm named after the motley crew
song Nona
there's an actual song named Nona and
I'm named after a motley crew song
that's epic is it like a dirty song or
is it no it's actually like a super slow
boring song but it's like we have to
pick we have to pick one song yes that
was it oh we're just gonna take the
greatest albums and just stack them
together pick a name that's how my
parents came home with it
I think there's know a lot of parents
came up with a lot of names but I mean
nowadays we we go up pop culture like I
you know say Jackson for example you
know that's probably a lot from from
Jackson teller from Sons of Anarchy like
that's gonna say Jemma Jemma right right
I mean that's it when I'm watching TV
when I'm watching a lot of movies and
stuff I've I'm not shape to be like that
is the coolest name ever I'm gonna lock
that in my memory bank for later baby
yeah okay cool so so known as southern
welcome to the junkyard lab podcast yeah
I'm happy to have you it's funny that I
so I originally when we were first
talking obviously I was originally like
oh man you know a lot about guns
carpentry woodworking you're recently a
mom you you're with Brandon Bartlett it
was just like one most amazing cool
awesome people and so I just wanted to
hear stories about Brandon mostly but as
we just went and we had had a quick
drink in just a conversation and caught
up just as friends - I feel like there
was a few more things that that bubbled
up to the surface that were a bit more
important to talk about so I would love
to dip into guns and carpentry and the
things that you are amazing at but let's
start with with motherhood you recently
you recently a mother you want to talk
about that yeah so I just had my child
first one bricks Lee is six months old
she's right about six months um
and that was a huge life changer like
you think you're a very stable and life
is just going well and then all of a
sudden like oh you're gonna be a mother
it's gonna be so amazing and then life
just will take a huge [__] sometime yeah
and just hit you with like all of this
knowledge that you never knew that you
could even grasp because you're just
having to take care of somebody that's
not yourself you have to be the most
selfless person you can which is
definitely hard after being single for
so long and just doing my own thing and
always being a very independent person
mm-hmm it's crazy and then just along
with that too like you never know how
much you can take as a person until you
are just pushed to your limits right and
I feel like being a stay-at-home mom
which is what I am technically right now
there's a huge stigma on stay-at-home
moms that you feel like everybody just
sees you as somebody that stays home and
chills on the couch and oh you just
catch up on your shows is the case yeah
you're just gonna stay home all day and
then the husband comes home and he's
like oh what did you do all day it's not
typical sitcom pain in their mind and
you have to explain everything and it's
it's a lot more than that it's it's
definitely in depth of what I don't know
I just yeah I thought I was gonna know
everything and I was gonna be all set
and then it happened and it was a
complete 360 of what I thought it would
be so when did you start changing like
okay so you found out you're having a
baby obviously that initial shock is
just a huge like well everything's
different but then you know you started
really changing like your perspective
we're talking about earlier perspective
hugely shifted was it was it during your
pregnancy or after you had fix it uh it
was definitely during because um like we
were talking about earlier I was on
medication and I had a quick cold turkey
what was that medication for listeners
uh I was on adderall okay and I was like
my adderall for years before that and I
quit cold-turkey so that definitely was
a jolt to the system and then also just
physically I had never had my body
changed like that before which was huge
it was just very different and I had to
accept that this was me and for sure it
was it was doing something for somebody
other than myself like I was growing a
human inside me I was doing something
very selfless and it was amazing it was
amazing but there were definitely times
where I felt not like myself yeah just
like you were like your interests and
stuff - did your interest start changing
- I mean I love snowboarding I recently
got into snowboarding like the year
before that and then all of a sudden it
was being told no like I can't go
snowboarding alright you can't go do all
these things you kind of kind of have
that badass attitude - I mean on the
outside looking and it seems like you're
probably someone who doesn't like to be
told now now you know yeah you're a huge
go-getter of course it's probably been
beneficial to your life a lot of the
times but yeah I can imagine people who
know something know a thing or two about
babies and all of a sudden you're
pregnant and they're like yeah you can't
you can't snowboard right and then when
I would ask my doctor and I was like so
what is what is the cutoff for
snowboarding and she was like staring at
me like I was crazy and like no I'm
serious but can I still go snowboarding
even though I'm pregnant she's like well
you could oh my god it's safe for the
child but she probably is just like okay
slap you right yes well you know I don't
think that as it you know of course
let's say a general Blanque is named and
of course nobody's bad like it's just
dangerous of course but there I don't
know I don't there's a lot of places
where me per se I'm like I don't think I
should even have an opinion towards that
like like I think if someone is a
professional snow or not professional
but like a really good snowboarder and
they trust their own ability to not fall
I you know I don't know I sometimes I
think the mental health is better for
the baby than being miserable in the
house like what if I don't know I was
definitely not a professional so I knew
I was probably gonna go tumble down the
hill and yeah
so how'd it go since you've been
snowboarding this whole time you never
stop right um so so being a mother
obviously changed you I don't want to
get too hung up on it but we did have a
good conversation about the adderall so
stopping that that's something that you
had been on for for a while the ADHD cuz
I and so I asked Nona because I the last
I don't know over the course of the last
four or five years I've been off and on
adderall myself trying to like figure
out what works for me and trying
different things and also using it as it
as an avoidance - in my opinion or in my
case but I I'm off of adderall now and
I'm able to manage my attention and I
found a lot of other ways to to help me
and I feel pretty dang sane being off of
it and it seems like in here you're not
on anymore are you okay
and so how you quit and it was it was
cold turkey at first
it was terrible yeah that's not good
thing to do Brannon could probably you
know relate to this a lot because he
watched me but he definitely the day
that I found out I was pregnant snatched
that bottle of adderall right out of my
hand because obviously it could you know
change how you're developing a child
inside of you and it was terrible there
was like some thoughts inside my mind
where it's like oh I could steal that
back and just like feel better and
instead Here I am at night laying in bed
just like cold sweats shaking yeah the
withdrawals obviously there withdrawal
symptoms but just like the the zaps of
like okay I have to restructure the way
that I think because this this thing
this drug this you know it helps you it
helps people I don't want to say with
ADHD because we you know we have an
in-depth combo about that but it's let's
just say with ADHD it helps anybody with
their focus and it's any drug any
Infanta means obviously of course hard
to get off and that was rough I mean it
seemed like I came off of that drug and
it was literally just like months of
solid naps
because I had no clue how to adjust and
when I was still working I mean I worked
all the way up until like two weeks
before I had her so I was still doing my
job
was that was that nice to you was that a
good thing to you do you think yeah yeah
of course I just read a lot of different
personalities some people prefer to just
be solemn but some people are like I
would really rather just keep going you
know I feel fine or whatever it is for
me I knew that if I quit because I am
the type of person that has to do
something like I can't just sit at home
it's making me crazy
being stay home mom I knew that if I
quit working and if I just stayed home
that I would just go insane because I
got to keep going yeah but it was rough
I mean I quit taking it and it was just
like solid naps we had even taken a trip
over to Hawaii and Brandon makes jokes
about it but i napped the whole entire
time we were like what are you supposed
to do when you're really good naps at
least they were good naps you opened up
the window you can hear the ocean but
it's like what do you do when you're on
vacation you're a few months pregnant
you can't drink isn't it funny how we
have we get to these vacations in so
Shane and I went on after a show we both
met in Arizona for a few David Caine it
was just like a small like oh let's we
were celebrating my degree or something
else well Becka but we were on hole 30
diet and so we weren't drinking and it
was funny realizing how used to drinking
we are you know and in we have fun and
we ended up having a great time of
course but it's funny when you when you
go to places when you're not drinking
whether it's pregnant or whatever you're
following diet or whatever you realize
you're like oh yeah like we have to
think of things to make our own fun
right we can't just get drunk and then
everything's fun that's kind of a I mean
that's a real thing that sort of happens
as an adult for a lot of people in our
ages is learning relearning how to have
fun without drinking yeah which is kind
of a big one for I mean I am a social
drinker so I love to go out and I was
even
I was pretty always said I would never
be the person that was like pregnant and
at the bar mm-hmm I was pregnant at the
bar all the time because I still wanted
Brandon to go out and have fun and even
though I couldn't drink I still wanted
to be present and around my friends
which most of the time that's at a bar
right and going out and so I said this
is a small town yeah and I don't think
that that's so wrong what do you think
about that now like now that you like
you've done it and your mother you've
been a mother for a few months like do
you think it's it's a weird stigma I
don't think it's that big of a deal I
definitely would say don't judge the
moms that are out of the bar yeah you
have no idea like that mom might have
spent her whole entire week in the same
pair of sweatpants with no makeup no
hair done and like that is her moment to
get out yeah let her house just let her
have some fun
like if she wants to take a shot of
water with her friends mr. Pittman yeah
I was definitely out like the week
before I had her yeah well okay I want
to know right perfect I want to make it
a it's just all right we're just gonna
set the standard of the junket I love
podcasts if you're pregnant you got a
baby okay be careful like don't get me
don't get next to a guy with you sound a
bar fight but come on have fun with your
friends yeah be yourself don't be
ashamed and also if you see somebody
who's pregnant just don't even think
about it
they're probably trying to enjoy their
life just like I am and return to your
conversation and so breaking into
motherhood obviously like so so just
switching any any prescription that
we're on you know there's plenty of
people everybody's on different
different prescription drugs and
whatever motherhood that's something
that obviously I'm not a mother and I
don't plan on being a mother so and
something I don't have to think about
but you know that's that that is that is
interesting to think that whatever
medication or whatever you're taking you
get pregnant and it's like oh shoot like
do I want do I want to have this in my
system do I want to did you also have to
do so like when you guys first got
pregnant did you start thinking of like
food and stuff too or what yeah I mean
I'm pretty I'm pretty more on the
healthy side I would say like our
household is obviously if anyone knows
Brandon Totino's on this half and celery
on the south right we're a little split
which bless his heart if he wants to eat
a block of cheese for dinner he can eat
a block of cheese for dinner block of
cheese and it's actually a reality it's
a reality where I will eat brussel
sprouts and he will eat a block of
cheese I mean he's doing kicking he is
he's still doing pretty good he's doing
very good and he actually will he will
eat things that I make he a Brussels
sprouts
he's eating greens okay so we're doing
very well like Mountain Dew no okay it's
crazy what's your what's your plan for
bricks are you gonna do no are gonna be
a no soda mom I was a no soda kid so I
think I'm with that yeah I know
I'm with no soda at least maybe I can
come back up if you really want to three
definitely not like a pizza pocket
dude there's just not two there's parts
of me where like you know looking
forward in the future whenever I have a
child I'm like I just want to go live in
the woods and not even I don't want you
to know the McDonald's exists I don't
wait to know that Dr Pepper is a word I
don't I just want you to never even
learn of any of these terrible foods and
things it's definitely hard but at the
same time it's like I'm so tired you're
gonna eat a box of mac and cheese I
don't even care right now but I
definitely lean more towards the healthy
side so and also my mom owns a juice bar
in town Rogers bar yeah definitely so
like augustana share all the time and
just like go grind up whatever we've got
to plug that real quick you want to
let's give a load down real quick do you
think yeah we should I mean it's okay
yeah it's a business that we both know
but it's also something that if you live
around here right did this is a mental
health podcast it's super small town my
mom opened up raw organic juice bar so
it's all organic
she just all of a sudden one day I was
like I want to I want to do something
for me oh cool yeah so and my friend
actually down in Redding California he
owns like multiple juice bars he started
his own roots company um and he's super
successful and I was like this is a
really great idea there's nothing in
town that is healthy for anyone I mean
what's the other healthy alternative is
just the health food store which nobody
really mean we have a health food store
yeah we do they just moved actually yeah
I mean okay but I mean if you compare it
so in 2019 2020 it's great there's a lot
of places in typical so you go down to
Portland it's every half a block you can
get and pretty fairly healthy yeah you
get the bowls the power bowls so what do
you guys have you guys have just like
typical how is it healthier than other
so I mean it's all organic and she has
all of her produce delivered to her so
everything is like prepared and washed
and up to codes and just she I mean she
just has like this crazy insane juicer
where you just shove all the vegetables
and the fruits inside of it and it just
comes out and that's all it is you don't
add anything unless you want something
added I mean she has like some crazy
things like bee pollen people yeah
she'll research how do you get bee
pollen that's heavy I have zero clue
where she gets it from but she'll
research all of these crazy things that
can help people and that's all I mean
that's all my mom has ever wanted to do
in her life is she just she's one of
those people that will just help anybody
anytime anywhere so she loves that
people will come into her store and just
be like hey I had this problem
you know she I don't know if I could I
don't know if I could she has a customer
that has ALS okay and she actually gives
her a free drink every single day oh and
my mom is just like I can't even charge
you I can't even make you pay for this
because I don't want to she's like I
just want to help you right so she'll
like research I think the bee pollen was
one of the items that she oh she
researched because he found it right she
was like I want to put all of the
ingredients that are gonna help you with
your symptoms beautiful and she just
goes from there I'm not saying she's
everything
right you like please don't ask my mom
for me no that's great that's a person
that she knew for a long time and that
you know I had actually known for a
while too
well that's the cool thing is when you
own your own business and when you live
in a small town it's like oh I can do
this thing I remember this the way back
in the day when I was a young kid and my
skateboard had broke in the skate shop
owner it was just a small little thing
like you know that board probably could
have cost him $15 but he was able to
make my day by like my board had broke
and he was like hey man I want you to
have this
I know you guys will have a lot of money
or whatever it was the situation I
remember exactly but just like letting
someone have a little bit of what you
have because it really doesn't hurt you
in it you know it's service that's right
and like I try to talk to my mom about
it and I'll be like hey like you know
what are your profit margins like
because I'm I used to be into the
accounting in my old job and my mom
would just be like I don't know I don't
know and I'm like mom you're a business
owner you have to know honestly I don't
know you do but but I want to provide
stuff to her community I'm like do you
even know what you're making like profit
wise and she's like I don't care well
yes she does
yeah she just wants to give it out to
the community in case everybody we do
get caught up with with I had on my
deejay I had a couple DJs a couple days
ago on the podcast and I was talking
about how me myself I I cornered myself
I had a couple years of building a
mobile DJ's business without realizing I
don't want to be a mobile DJ like so I
was like deep into and I just kept
accepting gigs and people like can you
do this and I'm like of course I can do
this and I'm like so I'll get the gear
to do this and then a few years like
you're into it so I think a lot of
people get momentum confused with what
they actually want to do so if she
doesn't want to own a bunch of other
stores and open a bunch of businesses
and make this all this complicated thing
then those are the perks that she does
and of course any business you should
you should keep tracking profit margin
but I I'm sure she has it all under
control
that's super cool so that's over right
next to Ross in Lane Bryant right right
McQueen you know what's funny is
yesterday on this podcast I had
and Bob who used to own the clothing
store that was in that location cutting
edge which is cool to just have you guys
back-to-back well well no no we dipped
our toes a little bit in into the mom
life you know our our age demographic of
a lot of people who listen to this is
around is around our age and so I did
want to hang up on that a little bit
longer
what are you know just between you and
Brandon you guys is mental health your
guys it's like mental just just seeing
life differently just changing just
growing up like becoming parents you
guys have the house now like all these
super exciting things we talked about a
little bit about you working a job that
was great job but it was comfortable and
you didn't feel as as fulfilled and I
think all those things are super related
yeah I mean just to touch back also on
like having a significant other that is
amazing that I will also just a
disclaimer to anyone out there that is
pregnant that who has a significant
other if you have someone that's
expecting just take 30 minutes out of
the day and have them research
postpartum depression mmm I mean I am so
lucky that I had Brandon who will
literally any question that I have like
man I don't know about this he is the
first one to pull up his phone pull up
Google and start researching like he
will say hi this a job and he'll just
research all day and just like I wish he
would post a tweet once in a while too
but that's okay he doesn't but I'm very
very lucky that Brandon research as much
as he did like he'll come home at the
end of the day and be like hey like how
are you do you need like time do you
need you need to go out and go do
something like he's always the first
person to be like you need to go do
something for yourself like let me watch
her you know he research like crazy on
postpartum depression so when you do you
think it helped me with struggling if I
did I was right yeah of course because
it's you know these are feelings that
are new to you you're experiencing them
alone you're experiencing a lot of
things alone for the first time in
certain to know that he's looking up
these things like he's assuring you
it was like he knew what I was gonna go
through before I went through it right
so that was really nice because he
probably read it on reddit your
girlfriend will be sad yeah it's like
hey I'm gonna stop this crazy train
before it even happens
so some postpartum depression did you
did you anticipate having those feelings
like did you even think about that
before he brought it up I was thinking
that it was gonna be rough just because
of I leaned so much on my medication for
adderall I leaned a lot on that like
whenever I was feeling sad or you know
down I would take it and then I would
just get this huge burst of energy and I
would go do something and my mind would
be so distracted that I wouldn't even
think about it but all of a sudden I
didn't have that anymore so I couldn't
take it
mmm so you have to face whatever comes I
actually had to be a human and face what
was in front of me which was really hard
at times I mean I was doing something
that I had never done before and then it
wasn't about me for once I was always in
control myself but now I'm I have to be
in control of a human child that's been
way bigger than yeah that has to rely on
me for life so that was really difficult
and I'm just really really lucky that I
had someone that actually put in the
time in the effort which makes me sad
because I feel like I see so many other
moms on social media that are reaching
out and the person that they should be
reaching out to is probably the person
that's in the house with them I see I am
sure I mean yes I see that on Facebook I
don't think a lot of things that he'll
post on Facebook what what they're
saying the words themselves aren't
always what their what their meaning I
think you know it's almost like they're
trying to say it to their significant
other through a social media yeah
well in a lot of times we don't even
know that we're pointing out these
things right sometimes our brain will
trick us our intelligence will try to
help us out here with these things so do
you know so now on the other side so how
do you feel now - are you doing better
postpartum depression that you're doing
that
I'm great I mean like obviously you're a
new mom you're gonna have days where you
just sit at home and cry but cuz there
are things you just can't control and
you don't know how to control them so I
couldn't imagine I you dude I have a
shame that I because we've been having
the conversation more lately it's
something that you know as I've been
dealing with my childhood hood stuff
that like would pretty much lead me to
ignore any like so what do you think
about a family in the future Jake or
what do you think about this in the
future Jake it pretty much that kind of
made me like dance around that subject
and avoid it so now that I've been
dealing with those things and have dealt
with them and in working more around
them Shane and I are having the more
more conversations around that too so
yeah and I think it's one of those
things also where once you have a child
it makes you realize why your parents
did what they did like when I think
about it and I'm like oh like you know I
didn't have the greatest childhood you
know my parents weren't perfect and then
I live my life and then I see probably
there's a reason why my parents did what
they did like you know that they're
their own people there were people
before they had me so they still are you
know trying to mesh their life into my
life and you know yeah we forget we just
see them as like no you're just my mom
that's who you are
it's like know that they're a whole
person outside of that they're just a
whole they got that whole thing going on
and that was my biggest issue with I
shouldn't say issue that was my biggest
struggle with having a child is that I
was such an independent person and that
I was such an outgoing person that all
of a sudden I was a mom and that's all I
felt like and so every single day it was
like you're a mom this is what you do
your identity is your identity is
stripped yeah that's fair so I mean
there are there praise the people that
can be stay-at-home mothers and just be
a stay-at-home mother but for me I knew
that's something that I could not do
like I have to I have to do something
for me also and for me to be the best
mom that I can I have to live my life
also
like I never wanted to be the
stay-at-home mom if I was a stay-at-home
mom that was only a stay-at-home mom I
wouldn't be the best mom that I could
for bricks Li and if I am gone for a few
hours of the day you know which my child
is an amazing sleeper so half the time
she's asleep anyways in the morning when
I'd be gone if I go to work and then I
come home and I'm enjoying the time that
I'm with her it's gonna mean more than
me being with her all day long as a
stay-at-home mother and not enjoying the
time that I'm with her right because
it's so stressful sometimes yeah of
course so I'll be a better mother to her
if I'm doing more of what I should be
doing and also raising her yeah of
course no I totally does you have to
balance these things you can't just show
up like you know you can be in the same
room as your child 24/7 if you want but
if that means that you don't get a wink
of sleep what's the point of you being
in the room if you can't fully take care
chuckles you're so exhausted or
something right you know I mean some
people can be a stay-at-home mom and
just be the perfect you know Pinterest
mother but I know that for me that if I
am NOT out in doing what I'm you know
creating and doing things that I need to
do like physically then I'm fulfilling
yourself as a human right if I don't
feel like my own self then I'm I'm not
gonna be the mother that I need to be
for her yeah and then I'm just gonna be
miserable and depressed all the time
just being a stay-at-home mom you think
what's the point of showing up yeah
yourself I would rather I would rather
be like a hundred percent for you know
six hours of the day than 30% for an
entire day yes II I I have I don't know
if this is super related but so me with
meditation meditation is such a huge
thing to me know that like I don't use
it as like a bailout or like a
preparation tool it's a daily thing for
me but I do often find myself like I
have had a few times where I've been
late to something but it's because I had
to get a meditation but sometimes when
I'm so stressed and have a lot of
anxiety going on it's better for me to
be 10 minutes late than be on time very
anxious so that 10 minutes that I took
to meditate
then really calm down made me show up as
a better person I apologize for being 10
minutes late
yeah I don't know if that's kind of
familiar no I mean it is because I feel
like to be a new mom there's like it's a
huge stigma because especially for
social media you feel like you have to
be at a certain standard yes with the
perfect clean house and everything and
you can see photos and stuff which is
you know all that stuff is so cool
because we can make an art out of green
human which is amazing but it's it's
just more it's more stuff right yeah I I
almost went in the reverse though okay
nobody knew I was pregnant until we get
writing remember I said I was like ask
if you wanted a beer or something and
you're like no and I was I was just like
not I was like I have no idea what's
going on
pretty yeah but nobody knew I was
pregnant because I didn't post about it
on social media huh uh-huh
so nobody actually knew it then I feel
like when you start posting more things
there are more people that are judging
you and so that is a really hard thing
for stay-at-home mothers because you
feel like you have to level up to every
other mother that's out there and so I
mean I feel like I have a lot of people
that will tell me that I don't post
enough like oh you don't post enough
about your kid you don't post enough
about this oh I get excited because I
see you have a new story and then
they'll click on it and it'll be
something like woodworking and not my
child a baby yeah and they'll be like oh
I guess so disappointed when you post
about your you know here's a picture of
a saw and not your kid okay yeah your
grandma's like it yeah hey your saw I
want to see there again I can't see a
baby well is will so that's the thing is
that that just that represents out loud
the what social media is right we kind
of think that it's all of us and then we
get situations like that where you're
like it can't be all of us because I'm a
mother but I'm also I love woodworking
I'm also a carpenter I'm also still a
person yeah and you can't like that
doesn't mean yeah you can't just like
alright this is a cool photo of my table
but let me make sure I put my baby on
the table so you don't get mad
right in this photo you know we've just
got to be aware that our actions are are
kind of chosen by other people's
opinions sometimes if we're not careful
so yeah and then like also too like I
have other people that are mothers that
are new mothers and when you talk to
them and it's like mom shaming is
totally real is it I never actually
thought it was a trick that I could
touch on hmm and actually relate to
until it happened to me because I you
know looking it up when I was pregnant
like researching and looking into things
and then I was like my friends aren't
gonna be like that like you know my
friends are gonna be my friends in
supportive no matter what and I've had
multiple friends like drop off not even
talk to me anymore
and then it's crazy because almost
sometimes you feel like you can't talk
to other moms because like you're like I
don't want you to think that I'm doing
this like forcing Lango tell the other
mom and you try to be supportive but
then it's like you almost can't talk to
other moms because if you don't do
things the way that they do things you
know what's funny is if you would all
just have the conversation about it
you'd realize it like we're all doing
those things it's just on Facebook we
don't you know it's funny we have these
things that get planted in our heads of
these perfect here here's what you do
and here's how you take care of a kid
and here's here's what all the the the
proper way to raise a kid but I mean the
truth is that nobody knows the proper
way you know I think I think a lot of
people are just figuring it out and
that's the best of all of us can do if
your child is alive and breathing good
if your if your kids alive okay so so
let's uh let's transition into guns and
carpentry really quick but let's just
before that any any girls who are around
our age you are are pregnant going to be
pregnant may be going through like the
after postpartum depression do you have
any maybe a little bit of advice around
that I would say definitely do your
research like for as much as the in you
know the Internet can be a tool
as much as a negative I could almost say
is if you do have a significant other
just push them if you have to and just
say hey take 30 minutes you know
don't play another episode of the office
and just watch this instead just look up
some youtubes and just research on
postpartum depression because if you
know more about it before it actually
happens you're gonna be able to prevent
it and help it rather than have to deal
and go through it and then try to fix it
right when you and of course you don't
think it's gonna happen to you you never
you know that's how all this stuff
happens but I so I actually had to just
because of the nature of what I do and
how I'm very loud about self-help and
stuff I get messages from a lot of
people I have had more than one recently
had a baby female friend who has hit me
up like I'm not doing so good
what's happening was postpartum
depression of course did they're doing
great now but it was it's something that
I don't know because I haven't mentioned
that the doctor's office meetings but so
do they maybe mention it they say like
hey keep it up here's a pamphlet or
whatever or is it no it's literally like
you'll go in for your checkups and
they'll give you a clipboard with
questions and you have to sit there and
fill them out anyway you're in trouble
if you say the wrong things I gave my
baby away or it's almost like you're
getting a quiz and so you'll want to
answer the right way so that you don't
have to be in trouble
you don't want to get a low score and
totally get that so it's almost like
you're obliged to like mark the good
answers so that you don't have
postpartum if that makes any know that
you almost feel like you have to lie
right because if you mark the wrong
questions you're gonna get a bad score
and they're gonna be like oh now it's
time to medicate you man so then it's
almost like you just you want to answer
the right way I get that I get that well
okay so so just listeners be wary of
that that's it's okay like known as
being she's being honest about it right
now I mean it's it's okay you're gonna
have those things man especially in a
small town especially with Facebook and
all the social media you're gonna want
to like show off and be the best mom
ever but like sometimes you just you're
it's kind of rough I can imagine I mean
I couldn't imagine it's if you're going
through it
it's okay and also be prepared for it
learn about it learn about postpartum
depression learn about like how
different thing is things are going to
be and you can and also the guys you
know be more like Brandon Bartlett just
just be supportive research your stuff
look up look up anything about
postpartum depression even just for five
minutes while you're taking it up do it
[Laughter]
tell me is it about Brandon Brandon will
take my phone and he will FaceTime with
my phone on his phone so that he can go
poop and watch bricks Lee we got an we
have bricks Lee's own iPads so that he
can FaceTime the iPad while he goes how
is he as a dad I imagine he's probably
just so fun amazing yeah like I
literally you would you would probably
think that he would just be the goofiest
just does he take it serious he he
almost takes it too seriously I love you
but sometimes he takes it too serious to
the point where he will get frustrated
because I am the mother and I can just
do it so easily and like I'm so you know
like I could call him a child so fast
because she's my dog see right because
there's the difference between mom and
dad but he'll just be like why can't I
call her why can't I do this that would
bother me too if I was like because I
would want you know like when you're
around dogs in a dogs barks at you you
want to tell the other person like
normally dogs like me you want to be
that one person who they're like
normally my dog hates everyone but they
like you you always want to be that so
if you want to be the around kids know
he's amazing I mean I'm very very lucky
because he's the person that will be
like a no I'll get up with her I'll get
out he'll get up all the time and I'll
get asleep so I mean that dude that that
takes in new parents I'm sure that that
takes so much work from both parties so
again just any new listeners wherever
you're at if you're having a child if
you're in your pregnancy if you're after
your pregnancy if you're a father if
your mother just just take a note where
you're at
realize that the other person's writing
hurt yeah yeah communicate yes
communication is like the biggest thing
because if you are quiet and you
self-loathing it for too long it will
just eat you up alive and if you don't
talk about it it is just this viral in
real quick I do get a little concerned
about like echo chambers too with this
something I want to touch on like so a
lot of us have friends who are you hit
them up and you're like hey for example
Brandon's doing this it's really bumming
me out in that girl that girl texts you
back and she says yeah [__] him
Brandon sex so yes so yeah be careful
you know you know talk [__] lightly and
have your fun of course life is worth
living of course but but be careful of
your echo chambers and friends of people
who are pregnant be careful of think
about the rest of their life not just
this moment think about the long-term
that what's best for the baby long-term
what's best for the for your friend
long-term you know if you have a problem
with your significant other there is no
other person to talk to than your
significant other that's so true Donna I
like that because that is how it's all
gonna be resolved your if you have a
problem that's where it's gonna end up
when it's us versus problem not me
versus you you post one thing on
Facebook and all of a sudden it's gonna
blow up and then it's just gonna create
however I can be even worse yes
something that I am obviously like I
already have but I will continue to do
so is point out just the weird illness
and follow of social media I'm not I
mean I love social media I think social
media is so cool in so many ways but
it's there's a lot of weird things that
that we're noticing now that it's been a
couple of years and in our age are the
people who were surfing the wave of
technology and its coolness and so now
we're at this age where were like hey
these things are kind of weird and we
haven't talked about them and they make
us act weird so um carpentry I actually
so so my father he was a carpenter he
was a wood worker but circumstance I
didn't learn the single I don't know
anything about woodworking I also worked
at a lumber mill for five years and I
ran the machine that smoothes the wood
and that's about all I know so yeah at
the planer okay yeah so
well I worked at the end of the plane I
ran the machine that stressed that but
so let's just I mean of course you know
you're not claiming to be a professional
like like or
you know like just giving everyone all
this advice or that you're just the best
woodworker ever but you have been making
some serious abuse stuff
shailen I send it back and forth like
the most recent table that you made the
hearing one one I remember the name for
it to you but that that's super cool so
how did you get into woodworking Nona so
I always had the father that would he
always wanted voice and of course he
ended up with two girls so growing up I
was just always you know instead of
doing ballet we would lay three tab on
her you know roof and I learned how to
do that kind of stuff it was always more
of like the man's work and so I never
really actually got into it until I had
bought my house in Long View I owned a
house and I started just doing small
projects and started redoing it and just
improving it and then it just kind of
like grew we were talking about earlier
where I had a desk job for seven years
and it just wasn't for me
and I would enjoy doing things that were
more of like physical labor rather than
sitting in a desk and so when I'm doing
those kinds of things it doesn't feel
like work it feels like I'm just doing
what I'm meant to do and so you know
more of like the carpentry lately was
more of a reason just for me to get out
of the house and just get a break from
life and you know raising a kid and just
take like a break from me time and so
when I just started building things and
then you know I would slowly start to
post about them it was like I got more
interest from people where they're like
hey what you're building is really cool
like what you make is really awesome I
want some of this and then you know I
all of a sudden kind of have like this
weird revelation moment and I up and
quit my job of seven years it was crazy
and I have a new job with the jage Kelly
and going into carpentry
well congratulations is super awesome
huge so obviously I want to talk about
carpentry but
really quickly graze over your we did
mention kind of your mindset of like I
don't really want to go back to this job
right it was it was kind of a what am I
doing with my life moment where I kind
of realized that sitting at a desk
wasn't for me because it's not what I
enjoy doing
so I mean I can go to work for eight
hours a day and sit at a desk but I had
to be medicated to do it right yeah we
were talking about that's kind of how
you you know you go get ADHD medication
and they're like oh now you can properly
do this job well it's you know just who
you are as a human being you know your
soul's essence doesn't do super well at
a desk right I had to be medicated to do
a job that I wasn't meant to do I if I
was doing the job that I was meant to do
I wouldn't have to be medicated to do it
because it was meant for me that's not
what I'm designed to do I mean if I was
out work working with wood every single
day I wouldn't I don't need it
right I don't need adderall but I needed
a door all to sit yeah you do accounting
numbers and work there you know because
that's not of interest to you any and we
all know plenty of people who can look
they get to accounting and they love it
they're great at it there's some people
who like would love to you know if you
want to sit at a desk and you do great
with it that's totally fine but when you
know in your heart of hearts that like
this is uneasy and I'm not focused on
this and whatever so so woodworking now
like what you're able to keep your focus
when you're woodworking is just you
think it's because you're passionate
about it and yeah I mean definitely
because I mean I think overall I will
say that adderal definitely changed my
mindset on how I do things because I
know that I can start something and
finish it it definitely taught me how to
do that but more of I enjoy doing it so
it doesn't feel like work like what I'm
doing doesn't feel like work I mean I
mean what's it what's the point of what
we're doing any times anyway you know we
kind of forget that we're not building
up to this thing like oh we're gonna
live this life once we get this thing
we're gonna be happy like I just don't
see why not like while in the midst of
you doing this thing that is making you
long-term happy why not enjoy that too I
just don't think we should enjoy one
hour of a victory because we suffered
for 10
I want to kind of enjoy all 11 hours you
know right and so like we were talking
about earlier like with medication and
everything and having to be medicated to
do a job
it almost was kind of a 360 on I'm not
meant to do this job even though I was
good at it I was making decent money and
I had free rein on everything I mean I
didn't have a boss that told me what to
do every single day and it was an
amazing job and it was definitely a job
that I would go back to if I had to but
I know that it's not something that I
want to do anymore because I was not me
doing it like I would come home every
single day and you know Brandon would
say oh you're not happy like I can tell
you're not happy of course he could
sense that you know right any any
significant other can tell you that you
come home and you still are carrying the
weight of work on your shoulders all
right I mean Shaylee knew that very much
but I wasn't willing to tell her that I
was so depressed like she knew that I
hated my job but I would just always
like but it's okay you know I try to
like but you do have a cheery guy you're
making that paycheck and you're like oh
this is a good paycheck I need to do
this I need to keep going I need to do
this to keep up that comfort is so
tempting in in a lot of our you know our
age alone but especially our age along
with being surrounded by so many mills
and in factory blue-collar work or
whatever it was kind of I guess maybe
different for you but you didn't kind of
a tomboy upbringing so maybe it was I
did yeah obviously with the guns and
everything I'm doing and well so so
we'll we'll go into guns too definitely
but so woodworking specifically so again
just congrats like that's so cool that
you found something that you enjoy and I
like you're able to monetize it which is
something that like I don't ever think
to really care about that much but it's
just something that you enjoy and you're
super dang good at it what what what is
it about not woodworking like like what
did you start with what was your first
project that kind of pulled you in well
I
I actually made something for Brandon
that was my first project what was it I
posted its I don't even know how to
describe it a geometric it's just it
looks kind of tribal ish it was just
like a wall art piece and I just like
got so intrigued with making every
single angle perfect so that it all fit
together and I spent hours and hours I
was like two years ago three years ago
it was like a something that I made for
him for Christmas yeah yeah and it took
so much time on it and it and then he
like loved it because it was something
that you couldn't buy from a store right
so that I actually meant something and
like I put my heart into it and it's
still hanging up in our house oh yeah
those things really do kind of as I get
older I things like that more than I
ever did yeah yeah I mean it definitely
took a long time like I was working on
it like random hours in the night and
definitely like putting everything I had
into it and then I did have my house
which I sold in Longview and so I
completely redid all the cabinets I
built doors I tore out all of the carpet
by myself I redid all the hardwood
floors by myself and the trim so yeah
what was your favorite part of that part
like if I Cal sided the woodworking part
like doing the house like revamp stuff
it was kind of like having something
that you can see a before and after oh
my god I love this wood after before and
afters are so satisfied oh man mowing my
lawn I think that might be I don't want
to narrow down that I love my my lawn
but like I think it might be just for
that one glance before I go in the house
at the end I think that's all I do it
like five hours of just intricately
mowing I want to make it look pristine
that three seconds of white right for it
on the house and I give a little glance
super slightly OCD when it comes to
things which is very difficult be great
with carpentry though it works out for
you right but also at the fact that I
can never deliver an item until it's
like perfect mmm it's like I just builds
a table but I like couldn't take it over
there until it was to my standards which
like some people don't have
as high as standards I do yeah it's like
oh I just need a table to eat off of but
I'm like no do it do it right I'm gonna
do it how did you do the the herringbone
one
okay so let's also just for any listener
describe herringbone just as a challenge
but uh how did you do that one to you
herringbone is like a diagonal chevron
plaid argyle yeah it's like a chevron
like a zigzag I would say this is
exactly I decide to be hilarious to make
you try to explain with no visual it's
like a staggered zigzag of course it's
hot you made the staggered zigzag piece
of wood right and you have to get it to
line up you have to do the angles and
you have to you know make sure that
everything is actually going to line up
before you make it perfect and I am the
person that will nail everything down
and then rip it all up if it's not right
so it's like oh do you prefer to be like
by yourself in your element when you're
doing this yes yeah that's that's how I
I mean my I think there's something to
be said about anybody's personal like
flow state but me you know a lot of
times even I'm doing a ton of things at
once oh I have like different projects
that I'm working on throughout five
hours so and I'm just like pacing back
and forth but if I'm by myself I can
kill it I'm just locked into what I need
to do and I'm just I'm not even thinking
about the time whatever I'm just doing
my work you know if it is it similar to
you or it's just like a flow State oh
yeah like I'll be out in the garage
and I'll just be like working on stuff
and then all of a sudden Brandon will
like open up the door and be like hey
you know real well yeah like what's the
time what's my time limit on this but
it's it's more of like a break for me
than it is a working of course so that's
just that that's fulfilling you know
that's that's the point of doing a
finding art and finding things that you
enjoy doing and writing what do you see
for for so lately you've been kind of
just doing a little bit of here and
there on the woodworking what what do
you see for let's say pipe dream let's
say daydream like like what would you
enjoy doing would you say with
woodworking if
all working out pipe dream I'll journey
out in my Carpentier apprenticeship and
then I will have just mic my own
day-to-day projects that I can do out of
my shop
yeah do you guys have a shop set up
house no we are going to build next
summer everything yeah next summer
that's not too far away hopefully next
summer yeah bypass all of the
materialistic items and just go straight
for shop right that's what you should do
Franek you say he's like everybody keeps
asking if we're gonna get married I'm
like oh a wedding feels super nice but
also we really want to show of course
yeah hey what's gonna make your life the
best that you know really weigh it out
don't try to impress anybody else or do
what everybody else wants way out what's
gonna be like you know you guys can
certainly get married but if that just
makes more frugal sense a couple years
down the line yeah I would love to learn
more about woodworking one of these days
like like I'm gonna make you show me one
of these days because I that's something
that I I feel like a little kid about it
but that it's something that I'm like
man that would be cool cuz because I do
like when things fit together very
exactly I like creating just anything
you know I think that I would enjoy
woodworking but I yeah I just I just it
was kind of like skipped around for me
so it's it's interesting to learn um we
are doing oh we're doing pretty sawing
on time but let's uh let's talk about
guns so um in the gun world known as
southern I so okay so here's why I am
interested in just knowing more about
guns just say generally as as someone
who I plan on getting a gun soon and I I
didn't want to be responsible gun owner
I have fired guns like I'm not totally
just like I've never touched a gun
before I'm comfortable holding a weapon
I understand the the safety around it
I've shot different types of weapons but
I don't have my own it's something that
you know before I have my own I want to
be comfortable with it I want to have I
want to know a lot about the weapon
that's in my house Shaylee of course
wants to know the same thing but the
reason why I'm getting weapon of course
self-protection is just nice to have a
gun
but I've been going by my [__] self
in the woods a lot lately and I just
keep thinking of a cougar attacking me
and how defenseless I really am I think
I have his knife and I think that I'm
gonna like fight a cougar yeah and it's
so last time I just went two weeks ago
and I had this moment where I was
totally chill I was even thinking about
Cougars or whatever but I got about a
mile and a half and I ran in and then I
took my air pod out and then I heard
like like you know like they yep being
like the Coyotes yeah and it turned on
this thing where I was like man like I
don't really know much about coyotes and
if they surrounded me I don't know if a
knife I don't know anything about Cody's
and then of course that projected me
onto this cougar thing because we live
in an area where there is Cougars scene
so self-protection is something
obviously you know I'd go pretty deep
into the woods these are just on trails
but I'm going to bring a gun because I
think it's safe what would you say for
me as someone who I'm not totally
foreign foreign to weapons what would
you give me what advice would you give
me starting out about weapons I would
say definitely if you have someone
around you who is accustomed to weapons
and who can help you with them
definitely reach out we are lucky that
we live in a damage that we have social
media where you can join any forum where
you can YouTube anything I mean if you
want to learn how to handle a weapon or
even just be comfortable with one you
have it all at your fingertips because
you have a phone now I totally never
even thought about that I'm searching
YouTube person but I never even thought
about like how to properly handle a
weapon
Thank You fun attack you can check
Instagram like 15 times a day but you
will never actually like log on to
youtube to actually research how to do
the silliest things right we use our
phones more of for basic day-to-day then
actually to use the internet for what
it's meant for I think that that show is
a perfect example of hey your phone
isn't really using you alright you are
using phones using this distraction
thing right and I'm lucky that I was
able to meet so many amazing people that
were so knowledgeable about
the topic and that I was able to go to
events and to shoot and to learn from
some of the best people like not just
the best people but I would say like for
women it's easier for women to learn
from women so when I would go to three
gun shoots
I mean I've traveled like pretty far
I've been to like Utah and the first one
I went to was South Carolina I flew all
the way over there and I met some
amazing people I mean Maggie Reece Becky
Ackley Jenner Eve's there like some of
the biggest names in shooting and to go
to Applebee's with them and go hang out
with them just like yeah it's like let's
talk about guns or what you talked about
the whole entire time yeah yeah to go
like and I mean it was like a three day
four day event where you would go and
travel I flew over to South Carolina by
myself
and it was like it was the worst
experience because hurricane Joaquin hit
the coast that weekend so we got
completely rained out but it was also
the best because I was able to just hang
out with the people that we were
shooting with who have similar interests
as you right and it's it's a massive
group of women that were just there to
shoot so all you're doing the whole
entire weekend is just talking about
guns and you're talking about shooting
and you're just learning from like some
of the best in the industry yeah and I
mean three gun is pretty crazy to wear I
mean it is thousands and thousands of
dollars and you were what's that three
good you said yeah so three guns so
you're a shooting pistol rifle a shotgun
oh okay okay okay and it's timed courses
so these are those you know those crazy
Facebook you know videos that you see
where like the six year old girl is
running around shooting the gun as fast
as she can in the wood and hitting all
the targets that's what pretty much what
it is they're courses so um I was
learning from some of the best people
and then growing from that was amazing
and just they're always like so
welcoming and inviting and willing to
help you out with anything that you
needed so I could imagine that that's
kind of where I
my confidence from and then also just
branching out in the gun community from
meeting so many different people from
going to different activities and just
different you know events I was able to
meet more people and just keep growing
in knowledge would you say that the gun
community general blanket statement is
is welcoming so I could be like at the
shooting range
I don't know thing I'm like hey man I'm
sorry to bother you but I just want to
make sure I'm using this weapon
correctly could you help me do you think
it's like open like that or is this
generally I say that with caution
because there is like that's a
percentage of you know that my tool
that's on his computer with his keyboard
that's just like oh you're doing this
wrong you're such a tool you know you
know like just critiquing every single
thing that you do look Akiba a keyboard
warrior keyboard warrior yeah it's
pretty much what it is
it's real life he would like there's a
small percentage of people especially
being a girl I would get that a lot too
where I would get messages and it was we
kind of we kind of touched the topic on
that where it was almost degrading
because I would get messages from guys
where they would message me and say
you're a stupid woman you don't know
what you're talking about you're just
here being a gun bunny
they call him gun bunnies but oh like a
snow bunny yeah you would be a gun bunny
and you would just go out and take
pictures of you holding a gun but you
wouldn't actually shoot it which there
are some women that do that I didn't I
would I loved shooting with such a silly
thing to have to argue against Jesus
Christ what a waste of your time there
right you know like like some dude
messages you that you have to like pull
out your phone and look at that [__]
yeah what a waste of time right jeez so
there's a lot of negativity in the gun
community but there's also a decent
amount of people who are very supportive
so that was very nice and also the
people that I met along the way were
just genuine good human beings who would
want to teach me it it was just very
eye-opening because I learned so much
from them
that it just made me feel confident
about myself which is half the reason
why people don't shoot and that people
don't carry is because they don't feel
confident huh
so most people that they don't want to
carry a gun is because they don't know
how to use it of course you know you
want to feel comfortable with that thing
right so I mean you can just good you
can go out you can buy a gun but if you
don't feel confident using it you're not
going to feel good about actually
meeting it when time comes yeah I think
you know just as much as so my friend
Spencer now we talked about if you're
going to go to the gym you should you
should learn how to have a mindful walk
by yourself first like before you're
gonna go run and do this first so before
you go out just like I need
self-protection I'm gonna go buy a gun
do you recommend like before you spend
your own money on a gun before you do
these things like going out and
experiencing shooting a gun maybe
finding a friend going to a shooting
range or something so so say a girl
wanted wanted a weapon before she just
goes and buys one and doesn't know
anything about it recommend she goes and
learns yeah I would definitely say do
not go to a big-name place do not go to
like a sports I don't mean to shame
people but don't go to like a
sportsman's warehouse or like go to
somewhere that actually means something
go to Bob's go to a small chain retailer
then what's the difference to you Nona
like just maybe the the personable I
mean like I don't mean like named Rob
but like somebody that Bob's is going to
want to inform you more about things
than somebody at Sportsman's Warehouse
that they're gonna want to just make a
commission I agree
okay so there's nothing wrong with
pointing that out that's right I mean
like go to somewhere that's like I mean
I use um like well I mean the many
places that I go like are I mean go to
go to like go to like a small chain cuz
small chain people like Gators guns in
Kelso is like super low-key and they're
honestly a family-owned business so
they're more about educating you instead
of trying to make a profit off of you of
course so they're actually trying to
help you they want you to be informed
they want you to know what you're going
to buy rather than a chain brand that's
trying to make a profit off of you and
just make a quota for a sale a big place
is of course like like this guy is he
hasn't manager breathing down his neck
Lee he better make that sale it's not
like does this person need a gun what
type of gun do they need what do they
know about guns you know these guns are
a serious freaking topic you know I
don't think they should be taken taken
so lightly you know so I mean if you are
just out shopping for a gun and you want
to talk to somebody about it definitely
try to reach out to people that you know
I mean there's never been a time that
I've had someone you know message me say
hey I want to learn more about guns or I
want to go shooting like I will
definitely try to make time in my day
and in my schedule to go teach somebody
who wants to learn yeah because as a
community I'm gonna want somebody who
knows what they're doing rather than
someone just packing a gun that has no
idea I think more people should should
be less afraid of it I think more people
should should learn because I think you
know I would be willing to bet that a
lot of people once they've had a gun if
you've never had a gun in your hand once
you got out and you shot it for a little
bit a couple hours and someone taught
you about it and you felt it in your
hand and you shot it a couple times and
you felt things I mean that alone just
interacting with a weapon is enough to
break down that like scariness of I
think guns are I don't wanna touch this
thing you know which which you know you
can have your opinions on it but I don't
know I think that there's a lot of
situations there's a lot of craziness in
the world where if you want to have a
weapon I think that's totally okay I
think a lot of people are like oh I'm
gonna carry mace but I'll never carry a
gun it's like well they're both weapons
so you're trying to you know stun or
hurt somebody that's trying to have you
ever experienced mace have you ever I've
never experienced never ever either but
I I've heard that it's um one of those
things where it's like I sprayed it in
this room and you're in the next room
and you're [__] like it's like you
know we see it at movies where they
spray it right in their eyes and
obviously they do spray around their
eyes for police and whatnot yeah I've
heard it's so gnarly that if you're just
in the room next door you're near it
it's just what's terrible is that I'll
carry a gun and a knife and I won't
carry mace I've never I've never owned
me may see me
I will never carry mace but I will carry
a knife and I'll carry a gun at least
just put him out of his misery
what's your have you ever been hunting
before liked it when you were younger
did you go hunting yes okay what sort of
hunting what's your background with us
so like I would like rifle hunt with my
dad
bow hunt never actually got anything
with you know it's one of those things
that can be so epic if you did you try
but like bow hunting is seriously hard I
perhaps to do a bow hunt it's something
that's probably because I watched way
too much Joe Rogan but I just want to
eventually for most of the people that
will like go and just say oh you're just
driving around in a vehicle like if you
actually do it the right way it's it's
pretty hard yeah but I mean growing up I
I did more of sports so I did trap team
in high school you did the what you say
trap team yeah like trap Club I know
trap craap yes are you saying that you
and your friends sold drugs out of a
sketchy house oh no trap and skeet is a
different type it's hilarious though
like pop culture now the word trap is
just so trap team is where you go and
it's actually a sporting event where you
stand with five you know other people in
a half moon circle and a clay pigeon is
shot out of a house and you take turns
shooting at it and it's the best out of
25 and that is how you're scored which I
did that in high school for a little
while I also did cheerleading at the
same time so guns and cheerleading
didn't mix too well so I had to quit
which obviously cheerleading cost more
so I had a quit trap but after high
school that is how I got back into
shooting again was I was a when you call
it a co-captain
co-captain instructor I mean they both
kind of paint the picture because I
don't know what you call it why is this
word coming to me a coach a coach yeah
yeah I go as an assistant coach for a
trap team for highschool and so it got
back into shooting and that's how I got
back into three gun and that's how I
started getting all into the gun world
all over again so I I know you're not
much let's talk about the branch from
kind of like you you do not as much into
it anymore but I do want to but before
we go into that and just wrap up for any
sort of like anybody who is interested
in guns anybody who is afraid of guns
who wants one for self-protection
they're interested in getting a gun but
they're just like I don't know I don't
know everybody asked you did you have
any advice of like the first steps from
not having gun not knowing anything
about a gun to learning or getting a gun
do you have any I would definitely say
if you are hesitant on getting a gun to
do your research before you do it reach
out to the people that have experience
with it I'm definitely 100% always
willing to answer a DM if it is about a
weapon if anybody reaches out to me and
says hey I want to go shoot I want to
learn more I want to be able to protect
myself I'm so willing to go help you
because I want you to learn the right
way rather than just knowing that people
out there have weapons that they're not
comfortable with in that course that's
almost more scary to me than you know
yeah you know a crazy person just out
there with a gun but it's almost more
teach each other yeah totally willing to
share any experiences any knowledge I
have and I do not play you know I do not
claim to be a professional of course I
am willing to share the knowledge that I
have rather than keep it to myself so
yeah like it's a competition so it's not
a competition I'm not trying to be
better than anybody else I would rather
make everyone you know have what I have
but I mean I also don't claim to be 100
well nobody ever said you did it but I
do think it I do appreciate that you you
know offering up so so anybody has
what's your Instagram handle just for me
what's this I'm gonna stuttered yeah so
listeners if you're if you're from the
area and you have any any gun questions
or you want to like you just feel
uncomfortable about it and you want to
feel comfort about it there's no damn
shame in that at all
so so just maybe shoot you
a question she'll give me an answer and
we kind of touched on it but I dropped
off of shooting before I even had a
child okay
I was dipping into I could say an
influencer like I started yeah like it
was almost like all of a sudden my
Instagram you know follower count
started to go up companies are sending
you stuff second picture right so I had
a couple companies I actually had a few
companies that would send me stuff I
mean I had people that like retailers
that would say if you go shoot anywhere
we'll send you all your ammo for free if
you go you know you just have to use our
name I'd say okay
I also had companies that would give me
just you know loads of money and gift
cards for free clothing free
advertisement and then it kind of
spiraled into will pay you for your
advertisement will pay you for your
pictures and I was okay with that at
first and then it grew into a demand
right which I thought I would be
comfortable with and I ended up not
being comfortable with that's when you
kind of realize like oh I don't know
this is the part of guns that I like
right like everybody wants to be an
Instagram influencer like I feel like
it's a huge thing like oh I want to be
you know like a person that you know
it's one of those crazy people that has
five hundred thousand followers on
Instagram and I got nowhere near that I
mean I was probably like it like five
thousand which is not a lot you started
to get that uptick for sure though right
that like oh here here it goes here it
goes like yeah I mean if you would have
kept doing exactly what you're doing you
would have you would have okay in here
yeah I mean I had a company that was
like paying me you know $50 a photo and
so even like $50 a photo you post you
know maybe even 15 pictures a month
which isn't really that big of a deal
for people that active that's just one
company right and that actively use
Instagram if you post 15 pictures like
that's nothing but times I buy $50 a
picture you're making a pretty good
solid and kind of all the gear that you
get to
right and I mean they would give me like
gift cards of like $500 yeah and it's
like that's a good sized gift card right
there right and I had boxes and boxes of
clothing just like hanging around my
house which just created clutter and
then it got to a point where all of a
sudden one day I was taking pictures and
taking of course everyone takes selfies
I was over analyzing them and I was over
analyzing them to a point where I wasn't
feeling good about myself and so this
company would be messaging me and saying
hey we need you to post you know two
pictures a week and I physically could
not bring myself to do it I would sit
there and I would sit there for an hour
look at a photo look at all these self I
mean I would take 100 photos and then
try to pick the best one and then out of
picking they're just like one sweatshirt
angle right like one t-shirt you're
trying to take the best picture and you
would critique yourself to the point
where you didn't feel good about
yourself and so I would take me hours
and I'm like nobody else has this
problem like you should be able to post
a selfie like no problem and I would sit
there and look and look and look and
look and look and I couldn't do it and
so one day I got to the point where I
couldn't do it to the point of almost
breaking down and having to message this
company and I said I can't do this
anymore and they're like well why not
why can't you take a selfie and just
post it like we're paying you it's easy
we're sending you free clothes free
money why can't you do this and I just
didn't feel good about myself I
critiqued myself over to the point where
I didn't like myself mm-hmm and it got
to the point where I almost felt bad for
the people that I knew that do like
Instagram influencing where you feel for
them and you just have to quit and that
was me and so like you can definitely
like scroll through my Instagram feed if
you look at all the pictures like small
and you can see where I started doing
guns and shooting and I got really into
it and it grew and it got big and then
it just stopped and I quit and even to
this day it still kind of affects me
because I can take a bunch of pictures
and I still won't post them I don't post
a lot so now you second guess what you
should or shouldn't be posting right in
it you should just be this thing that
you don't think about you're like this
is my Instagram because whatever I want
right but now I have a bunch of people
and I mean I I don't have like quite a
fall I mean I like a few thousand
followers but like some of them still
follow me for the pack you know that I
shotguns right but I don't really post
about guns anymore so a lot of them
unfollowed me yeah so I felt like I
almost had like a stigma that I had to
keep up with it to satisfy other people
well you have that's the thing is like
these people like that person that I was
and when you come to realize that I'm
not always that person like you know I
can't be that person and I I was really
into that person for a while but it's
not who I am fully and then it feels
kind of weird like I mean you know we
gotta remember technology social media
that's a new thing for a man's it feels
weird to like you know even having
people unfollow you because you're not
into that thing no more like oh so I'm
I'm not interesting do you know and it's
nothing against them it's like dude you
should definitely not follow things that
you're not interested in I think
everybody should follow that but it's a
weird thing right it's it definitely
does something different in our brains
yeah and I just it got to me where I
felt so bad doing it that I didn't want
to encourage it anymore and then when I
started to see other people who were
posting all these things and when I
would scroll through a feed and see a
product and I would see it and it's like
I need this but do I actually need this
or do I need it because someone else is
telling me I need this yeah you wouldn't
know you need it if in your son right so
I don't want to be that person that
pushed other products on people because
they didn't meet it I didn't want to
push it because I don't want to be the
pushin person like the person pushing it
on other people it's it's a position
that you never thought you
realize existed right you're like I
didn't run said I would be even in this
position to where I would have to be
second guessing like my you know am i
treating other people's time as valuable
you know it's it's it's something you
have to actually kind of think of as
influencer right or even just stepping
into the foot of it of an influencer
it's it's this new thing that's super
cool and awesome but then it happened
you know like you or someone I think
what's what's happening what happened
with you is you never thought that that
kind of [__] what happened to you would
be no never you know it's crazy cuz then
like I mean just like this smallest like
you know the John wick movies where it's
I love John wick but it's when I first
started shooting the guy who trains John
wick the Turin tactical guy he messaged
me on Facebook and he was like hey
thanks for the ad like great to you know
connect with you and I had no clue who
he was so I totally brushed it off but
like at that moment when I come back to
it I was like shoot I could have been I
could have been something maybe I could
have went down there and like hung out
with him and like learned from him but
at the time I was like so young and kind
of like naive to the whole like
Instagram influencing kind of thing
where I was just touching my toes in the
water and I got out of it so fast that I
like it wasn't it wasn't healthy for me
yeah I mean that's the thing is you you
know you could have although that would
have been probably awesome and I'm sure
you wouldn't have regretted it by any
means but you know maybe that would have
sucked you a little bit farther maybe
this whole like in between I don't know
how I feel about this thing man that
would have lasted a couple years if you
would have done that you know sometimes
we get sucked into I was talking about
like my mobile DJ gig I you know I was a
few years into mobile DJ until I
realized so I was like I don't want to
be mobile too ya know
you know opportunities are wonderful but
if they don't really match we got to
take a step back Mike to smash our end
goal like does this make me happen in
the long term you know so so now that
you don't so I feel like you you stopped
the momentum of like the Instagram
influence are coming at you so sort of
thing
and then you know just family in a child
and ranan just different things where
you at with with just the enjoyment of
shooting guns and that sort of thing now
I definitely it's more of since I have a
child I feel like I need to have more
protection especially in this day and
age I don't know she's well I I see all
of those posts on Instagram I'm not even
Instagram at Facebook where it's like
the sex child trafficking where my child
was almost stolen at the store like some
guy was following me around this is my
boil makes my boy so mad where I just
want to be like I gotta get a gun be the
mama bear that you say you are yeah
there you go
I just want to like hey there's nothing
wrong with that I you know I think that
we should all find ways to protect
ourselves you know where it's it's a
different view for us we live in a place
where it is safe to walk to the store
there's a woman you know for the most
part I'm sure you guys you probably have
thoughts in your head that I've never
even fathomed you know just being a
woman you know I always think of like
walking to your car in the dark as a
woman that's a different experience than
me yeah of course definitely is so so
you just have a different life but but I
think that in places like like busy
places and in situation you just brought
up like people being being proud and
unsafe places you don't be afraid to
protect yourself don't be afraid male or
female and that's the thing you know if
you don't know much about guns like even
as a guy you don't have to be a stud
with know everything about guns just to
get one for protection like you you can
have a gun if you want protected and
feel safe and you can just have a basic
knife like some ninja stars yeah or a
longbow all right Nona if you had to
okay Lord of the Rings
version so if there was this this fight
and you had to choose like what your
character is like your this for 10 years
this you got a your if you choose a
dwarf or your dwarf what are you gonna
be I'm going to choose Legolas I'm
well I would want a wizard staff Oh
[__] you just you just cheated I
forgot about that
all right well I'm just [__] fighting
dwarfs and I'm fighting with a 9-mil at
home I'm taking a wizard staff out to
the grocery store mill at home I got
this wizard staff epic all right well
we're getting up here in time let's go
ahead and round it out let's say if you
have any any little small bits of advice
for any listeners you want to leave them
with anything if you need a weapon to
protect yourself if you need a weapon to
protect yourself to get a [__]
switchblade notice other I appreciate
you thank you for offering these
listeners a little bit of advice and a
little bit of a different perspective
thank you for being brave and sharing
the the newness of life that you're
experiencing lately I feel like
listeners and me got a lot got a lot of
those conversations so Nona Southard I
appreciate you and listeners if you have
any questions about guns or protecting
yourself or just being a badass person
new mom things or new moms death mom
support mom's mom support mom's just
cheap shooter message Wynonna southern
on Instagram and then just touching on
one more time postpartum depression it's
very real it's very ok yes it's it's a
very normal thing yeah talk about a lot
yeah and then also just on that same
page girls moms of small communities
none of you are against each other no
you're not against each other mom mom
shaming is not cool yeah that shit's
corny be nice you know seriously be nice
be nice all right junkyard love podcasts
out
you